<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE rss PUBLIC "-//Netscape Communications//DTD RSS 0.91//EN" "http://static.kdenews.org/mirrors/my.netscape.com/publish/formats/rss-0.91.dtd">
<rss version="0.91">
    <channel>
        <title>KDE Dot News</title>
        <language>en</language>
        <link>http://dot.kde.org/</link>
        <description>KDE Dot News: KDE News on the Dot.</description>
        <image>
           <title>KDE Dot News</title>
           <url>http://www.kde.org/dot/Images/kdedotnews_88x31.gif</url>
           <link>http://dot.kde.org/</link>
           </image>
        <item>
           <title>KDE Launches User Forums</title>
           <description>
             The KDE Community today launches the new &lt;a href="http://forum.kde.org/"&gt;KDE
Forum&lt;/a&gt;. The new forum uses the bulletin board software &lt;a
href="http://www.mybboard.net/"&gt;MyBB&lt;/a&gt; offering users, developers and people
interested in KDE a place to help each other, discuss KDE-related topics and
exchange ideas. The KDE Forum complements
&lt;a href="http://userbase.kde.org"&gt;KDE's UserBase&lt;/a&gt;, the home for KDE users
as a valuable support resource.






&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Forums&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The forum offers a number of categories&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forum&lt;/strong&gt; lists announcement and has a section for
        providing feedback about the forum.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;News Releases&lt;/strong&gt; you can discuss the latest and
        greatest KDE news, and even follow commits to the KDE codebase in real
        time.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The largest category is for &lt;strong&gt;Users&lt;/strong&gt;, different KDE apps
        and modules are covered in the sub-forums here.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Operating Systems&lt;/strong&gt; category gives those seeking to
        discuss platform-specific issues a place to post to. &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Want to get feedback about your code? Need to get more detailed
        explanations of a certain topic? The  &lt;strong&gt;Developers&lt;/strong&gt; section is
        there for you. &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Other Languages&lt;/strong&gt; has pointers to local KDE Forums.
        These forums are not part of the "KDE Forums" proper, but nevertheless a place
        you might find answers to your questions and like-minded people. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The KDE Forums admins have set the structure up as a starting point. Sub-communities or
interesting parties can request their own subforum. The KDE Forum team is working
on integrating the new KDE Forum with KDE's existing infrastructure by means of
IRC bots that can announce new threads and posts on IRC channels, by briding
forum posts to mailinglist messages and by offering RSS feeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;MyBB Released as GPL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with KDE, the developers behind MyBB have
&lt;a href="http://community.mybboard.net/thread-38942.html"&gt;decided to release&lt;/a&gt;
their forum software under the terms of the GPL Version 3. Chris Boulton, project manager
at the MyBB Group said "&lt;em&gt;The KDE forum guys have come to us with the wish to use our
forum software. In this process, we needed to clear out our licensing to
make it easier for the KDE community to make use of MyBB. As a result of that, we
have now released the MyBB forum under the terms of the GPL. This was very well-received
by the community around MyBB&lt;/em&gt;". Entirely in the spirit of Free Software, the KDE
Forum team has already contributed a number of plugins for MyBB, supporting the
decision taken by the MyBB team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob la Lau, initiator and administrator of the KDE Forum adds "&lt;em&gt;We've
chosen MyBB as it stands out head and shoulders above other candidates we have
considered to adopt for the new KDE Forums. We know that a good piece of
software makes a lot of difference to the user, after all we want to create a
nice place for everybody to chat about KDE and related questions.&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sebastian K&amp;uuml;gler, member of the KDE e.V. Board of Directors explains where the
new KDE Forum fits into KDE communication infrastructure, "&lt;em&gt;We've come to
believe that mailinglist don't cut it for all users. KDE becoming increasingly
widely used should also offer  a place for those that aren't familiar with the use of e-mail
for such discussions. The new KDE Forum complements KDE's new end-user
knowledge base Userbase that was launched last month. At the same time,
we're really happy to see that after our request the MyBB team has decided
to release their forum software under the terms of the GPL&lt;/em&gt;".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So get your account and join the discussion now.
&lt;/p&gt;





           </description>
           <link>http://dot.kde.org/1223822418/</link>
           <guid>http://dot.kde.org/1223822418/</guid>
           <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2008 07:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
           </item>
        <item>
           <title>Amarok 2 Second Beta Released</title>
           <description>
             The Amarok Squad is proud to announce the second beta release of Amarok 2.0. This release includes a lot of bug fixes and improvements, like the switch from SQlite to MySQL-embedded. The LibriVox service is back, as is lyrics support. Please read the &lt;a href="http://amarok.kde.org/en/node/554"&gt;release announcement&lt;/a&gt; for a detailed list of changes since the release of Beta 1 and more.

&lt;br&gt;&lt;div style="border: thin solid grey; padding: 1ex; margin: 1ex; float: left"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://static.kdenews.org/jr/amarok2-beta2.jpg" width="480" height="320" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The most significant change in this release is the switch from SQLite to MySQL-embedded as the database backend. MySQL-embedded allows us to use the performance increase of the popular MySQL database, while avoiding non-trivial configuration that comes with a standalone server. Most noticeably, you will see much improved performance of collection scanning and searching, especially with very large music collections.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
More generally we have fixed a huge amount of bugs, bringing Amarok 2 one step closer to the stability you would expect for your daily music needs. While not quite stable quality, we encourage our users to test this release and continue submitting bug reports. Already this beta version is good enough for daily use in many cases.  
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We hope you enjoy this release which we have worked so hard to produce. Stay tuned for upcoming releases, and please do not forget to donate for &lt;a href="http://amarok.kde.org/en/node/548"&gt;Roktober&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;/p&gt;


           </description>
           <link>http://dot.kde.org/1223401559/</link>
           <guid>http://dot.kde.org/1223401559/</guid>
           <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2008 10:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
           </item>
        <item>
           <title>PolishLinux Interviews KPackageKit Authors</title>
           <description>
             PackageKit is a system designed to make installing and updating software on your computer easier. The primary design goal is to unify all the software graphical tools used in different distributions. KPackageKit is the KDE interface for PackageKit. &lt;a href="http://polishlinux.org/kde/kpackagekit-interview/"&gt;Polishlinux.org spoke with Adrien Bustany and Daniel Nicoletti&lt;/a&gt; the Packagekit-Qt and KpackageKit developers, about the emerging possibilities in the process of managing software on your desktop.

           </description>
           <link>http://dot.kde.org/1223337689/</link>
           <guid>http://dot.kde.org/1223337689/</guid>
           <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 17:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
           </item>
        <item>
           <title>Support Amarok This Roktober '08</title>
           <description>
             Another year has passed and the Amarok team wants to celebrate with its fans: it's &lt;a href="http://amarok.kde.org/en/node/548"&gt;Roktober&lt;/a&gt; again! This is the time of the year when the Amarok team reviews what they have achieved during the past year and call for your help for the coming year.



&lt;br&gt;&lt;div style="border: thin solid grey; padding: 1ex; margin: 1ex; float: right;"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://mark.kollide.net/fundraiserWoofy.jpg" width="420" height="475" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Your donations of time and money make it possible to create the awesome music player you love so much.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Our aim for this Roktober is to raise &amp;#8364;10,000. Our budget is aggressive, but as costs go up, and our plans get more complex, we have to raise the goal. As in past years, for every &amp;#8364;10 donated, you will receive one entry in the drawing for an iAudio7. This year we have two grand prizes and we will also give t-shirts to 4 second chance winners.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At Akademy 2008 Amarok won the prestigious &lt;a href="http://amarok.kde.org/blog/archives/796-We-Win!.html"&gt;Best Application&lt;/a&gt; award at the &lt;a href="http://www.kde.org/history/akademyawards/"&gt;Akademy Awards&lt;/a&gt;. Your donations make it possible to continue this work, producing what is the best music player for Linux, and will shortly become the best music player on any platform. Amarok 2 is about to let a second beta out of the bag and we look forward to a ground breaking final release.
&lt;/p&gt;




           </description>
           <link>http://dot.kde.org/1223140303/</link>
           <guid>http://dot.kde.org/1223140303/</guid>
           <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 10:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
           </item>
        <item>
           <title>KDE 4.1.2 "Codename" Finally Out</title>
           <description>
             Two days later than initially planned, "Codename" (or more traditionally KDE 4.1.2) &lt;a href="http://kde.org/announcements/announce-4.1.2.php"&gt;was released just a few minutes ago&lt;/a&gt;. The delay was caused by binary incompatibility issues in the branch. Those have been resolved so we are now looking at a stable release. 4.1.2 is another one of those monthly bug fix and translation updates. No new features are allowed into the 4.x/ branches, so no new features went into KDE 4.1.2, but some nice bug fixes instead. David Faure has fixed a long-standing and annoying performance issue when deleting files using KIO, so you can now accidentally &lt;a href="http://www.kdedevelopers.org/node/3683"&gt;delete your home directory 32 times faster&lt;/a&gt; For the more faint-hearted, it will also work well with other files. You can read about all the changes that went into &lt;em&gt;Codename&lt;/em&gt; in the &lt;a href="http://www.kde.org/announcements/changelogs/changelog4_1_1to4_1_2.php"&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt; which offers links to the comprehensive SVN log files.
KDE 4.1.2 is a recommended upgrade for everybody running KDE 4. The next feature release of the KDE workspace and applications will be in January 2009 when 4.2.0 will be upon you.


           </description>
           <link>http://dot.kde.org/1223050704/</link>
           <guid>http://dot.kde.org/1223050704/</guid>
           <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 09:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
           </item>
        <item>
           <title>KDE Commit-Digest for 21st September 2008</title>
           <description>
             In &lt;a href="http://commit-digest.org/issues/2008-09-21/"&gt;this week's KDE Commit-Digest&lt;/a&gt;: Various work across &lt;a href="http://plasma.kde.org/"&gt;Plasma&lt;/a&gt;, including improved applet handles with monochrome icons, work on the Weather Plasmoid and the start of an extender-based notification applet. Continued development in PowerDevil, including support for suspend. Long-standing "slow deletion of many files" bug is finally fixed. A System Settings module for choosing the default file manager. Basic implementation of red eye reduction in &lt;a href="http://gwenview.sourceforge.net/"&gt;Gwenview&lt;/a&gt;. A generator for G3/G4 fax documents in &lt;a href="http://okular.org/"&gt;Okular&lt;/a&gt;. Support for filter plugins in &lt;a href="http://kst.kde.org/"&gt;Kst&lt;/a&gt;. More work on code completion in &lt;a href="http://www.kdevelop.org/"&gt;KDevelop&lt;/a&gt; 4. Start of a D-Bus interface in Lokalize. First working implementation of KMenuEdit global shortcuts. Work on supporting different resources in the &lt;a href="http://pim.kde.org/akonadi/"&gt;Akonadi&lt;/a&gt; OpenSync plugin. The return of Ark context-menu actions. Liechtenstein, Oman, and San-Marino maps in &lt;a href="http://edu.kde.org/kgeography/"&gt;KGeography&lt;/a&gt;. Previews of slide transition effects in &lt;a href="http://koffice.kde.org/kpresenter/"&gt;KPresenter&lt;/a&gt; now happen directly on the affected slide. A &lt;a href="http://www.koffice.org/kformula/"&gt;KFormula&lt;/a&gt; widget is extracted from &lt;a href="http://koffice.org/"&gt;KOffice&lt;/a&gt; and moved into kdelibs for use in other KDE applications. Work on porting Keep, a backup utility, to KDE 4. &lt;a href="http://nepomuk.kde.org/"&gt;NEPOMUK&lt;/a&gt; query libraries move from kdereview to kdebase/workspace, with the search KIO slave moving into kdereview. A KDE 4 port of KnowIt, a note taking application, is imported into KDE SVN. &lt;a href="http://eigen.tuxfamily.org/"&gt;Eigen&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 Beta 1 is tagged for release. &lt;a href="http://commit-digest.org/issues/2008-09-21/"&gt;Read the rest of the Digest here&lt;/a&gt;.
           </description>
           <link>http://dot.kde.org/1222872204/</link>
           <guid>http://dot.kde.org/1222872204/</guid>
           <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 07:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
           </item>
        <item>
           <title>OpenExpo Winterthur</title>
           <description>
             The second &lt;a href="http://www.openexpo.ch/"&gt;OpenExpo&lt;/a&gt; for this year was held in Winterthur on 24th and 25th September. All was perfectly organized by &lt;a href="http://www.ch-open.ch/"&gt;/ch/open&lt;/a&gt;. Read more about KDE's presence at the show.






&lt;br&gt;&lt;div style="float:right; border: 1px solid #888; margin:5px 5px 5px 0; padding: 5px; width: 180px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://static.kdenews.org/danimo/claudia_openexpo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.kdenews.org/danimo/claudia_openexpo_small.jpg" border="0"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;Claudia, our Administrator.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KDE had a well visited booth, where Luca Gugelmann, Alexandra Leisse, Claudia Rauch and Eckhart Wörner answered questions, collected feedback and took care of the smaller and bigger sorrows of our users while Mark Kretschmann added some Rock 'n Roll feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On wednesday Alexandra Leisse gave a well received talk about the upcoming release of KOffice 2. The slides (in German) are &lt;a href="http://koffice.kde.org/presentations/troubalex_winterthur.odp"&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;. A video of the whole talk will be online later this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everybody who made this presence a success.&lt;/p&gt;

           </description>
           <link>http://dot.kde.org/1222632260/</link>
           <guid>http://dot.kde.org/1222632260/</guid>
           <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 13:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
           </item>
        <item>
           <title>KOffice 2.0 Beta1 Released</title>
           <description>
             The KOffice team is proud to announce the first beta of KOffice 2.0. The goal of this release is to gather feedback from both users and developers on the new UI and underlying infrastructure. This will allow us to release a usable 2.0 release, demonstrating our vision for the future of the digital office to a larger audience and attract new contributions both in terms of code and ideas for improvements.  Read on for more information or see the &lt;a href="http://koffice.org/announcements/announce-2.0beta1.php"&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt; and download it from the &lt;a href="http://koffice.org/releases/2.0beta1-release.php"&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;.








&lt;br&gt;&lt;div style="border: thin solid grey; float: right; padding: 1ex; margin: 1ex"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.koffice.org/announcements/pics/2008-09-25-kpresenterbeta1.png"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.kdenews.org/jr/koffice2-beta-kpresenter.png" width="430" height="341" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first beta release of KOffice 2.0, and the first version we encourage users to download and try out. After a very long development cycle KOffice is now in feature freeze. The development team will from now on shift focus from new features to bug fixes until 2.0 is released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The release team has decided that the following applications are mature enough to be part of 2.0: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  KWord,   Word processor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  KSpread,   Spreadsheet calculator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  KPresenter,   Presentation manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  KPlato,   Project management software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Karbon,   Vector graphics editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Krita,   Raster graphics editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chart application KChart is available as a shape plugin, which means that charts are available in all the KOffice applications in an integrated manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Highlights of KOffice 2.0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KOffice 2 will be a much more flexible application suite than KOffice 1 ever was. The integration between the components is much stronger, with the revolutionary Flake Shapes as the central concept. A Flake Shape can be as simple as a square or a circle or as complex as a chart or a music score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Flake, any KOffice application can handle any shape. For instance, KWord can embed bitmap graphics, Krita can embed vector graphics and Karbon can embed charts. This flexibility does not only give KOffice unprecedented integration, but also allows new applications to be created very easily. Such applications could target special user groups such as children or certain professions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Unified Look and Feel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the applications of KOffice have a new GUI layout better suited to today's wider screens. The GUI consists of a workspace and a sidebar where tools can dock. Any tool can be ripped off to create its own window and later be redocked for full flexibility. The users setup preferences are of course saved and reused the next time that KOffice is started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="border: thin solid grey; float: left; padding: 1ex; margin: 1ex"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.koffice.org/announcements/pics/2008-09-25-kword-windows-beta1.png"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.kdenews.org/jr/koffice2-beta-windows.png" width="430" height="323" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Platform Independence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of KOffice is available on Linux with KDE or GNOME, Windows and Macintosh. Solaris will follow shortly and we expect builds for other Unix versions to become available soon after the final release. Since KOffice builds on Qt and the KDE libraries, all applications integrate well with the respective platforms and will take on the native look and feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Native Support for OpenDocument&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KOffice uses the OpenDocument Format as its native format. This will guarantee interoperation with many other Office packages such as OpenOffice.org and MS Office. The KOffice team has representatives on the OASIS technical committee for ODF and has been a strong participant in the process of shaping ODF since its inception.&lt;/p&gt;







           </description>
           <link>http://dot.kde.org/1222347961/</link>
           <guid>http://dot.kde.org/1222347961/</guid>
           <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 06:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
           </item>
        <item>
           <title>UserBase Goes Live!</title>
           <description>
             The KDE community is pleased to announce &lt;a href="http://userbase.kde.org"&gt;UserBase&lt;/a&gt;. UserBase is the new end-user wiki for KDE and complements &lt;a href="http://techbase.kde.org"&gt;TechBase&lt;/a&gt;, the wiki aimed at developers. It will contain tips and tricks, links to where to get more help, as well as an application catalogue giving an overview of the different kinds of programs that KDE offers.



&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;After weeks of preparation and vivid discussions at Akademy, UserBase is ready to help users with their day-to-day problems and is awaiting contributions from the wider community. &lt;a href="http://userbase.kde.org/Talk:Welcome_to_KDE_UserBase"&gt;A Talk page&lt;/a&gt; is available, for suggestions and requests for content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The KDE community hopes to offer information that is better tailored to the needs of the KDE users by offering them a place to share their knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions regarding UserBase please contact the Community Working Group at community-wg@kde.org.&lt;/p&gt;



           </description>
           <link>http://dot.kde.org/1221824063/</link>
           <guid>http://dot.kde.org/1221824063/</guid>
           <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2008 04:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
           </item>
        <item>
           <title>KDE Commit-Digest for 14th September 2008</title>
           <description>
             In &lt;a href="http://commit-digest.org/issues/2008-09-14/"&gt;this week's KDE Commit-Digest&lt;/a&gt;: "Shortcut Scheme" support allows creation of shortcut themes (Emacs, etc.) for use in KDE applications. A "Media Player" runner (with support for &lt;a href="http://amarok.kde.org/"&gt;Amarok&lt;/a&gt; 2), more work on panel hiding, and support for text zoom in the "Web Browser" Plasmoid in &lt;a href="http://plasma.kde.org/"&gt;Plasma&lt;/a&gt;. The "Weather Station" applet moves to kdereview. More refinements in PowerDevil, in preparation for a move to kdebase. Lots more functionality in Attica, the Open Collaboration Services desktop client. Start of session support in KDevPlatform (the basis of KDevelop 4). A "McCabe cyclomatic complexity metric engine" in &lt;a href="http://www.kdevelop.org/"&gt;KDevelop&lt;/a&gt; 4. Support for image rating (using KRatingWidget) in the interface of &lt;a href="http://kphotoalbum.org/"&gt;KPhotoAlbum&lt;/a&gt;. Progress towards real levels in the KPicross game. More work towards Jabber-based network games in &lt;a href="http://home.gna.org/ksirk/"&gt;KSirK&lt;/a&gt;. A "black screen" presentation feature in &lt;a href="http://okular.org/"&gt;Okular&lt;/a&gt;. Various work in &lt;a href="http://pim.kde.org/akonadi/"&gt;Akonadi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://pim.kde.org/"&gt;KDE-PIM&lt;/a&gt;. Start of the NetworkManager KControl module (for use in System Settings, etc). Incremental scanner support returns to Amarok 2. New plugin to specify the download order of multi-file torrents in &lt;a href="http://ktorrent.org/"&gt;KTorrent&lt;/a&gt;. Passwords saved per LDAP login (not host) in KRDC, greatly improving the experience for LDAP administrators. An OpenGL demo to demonstrate various parts of &lt;a href="http://eigen.tuxfamily.org/"&gt;Eigen&lt;/a&gt; 2. Some work to make KDE application dialogs fit into 1024x600 pixels. Merge of improvements to KFontInstaller. Import of QuickSand, an alternative front-end for KRunner. A proof-of-concept "&lt;a href="http://decibel.kde.org/"&gt;decibel&lt;/a&gt;-kde" library for representing contacts "based on the representation used by Kopete". WLM protocol imported into &lt;a href="http://kopete.kde.org/"&gt;Kopete&lt;/a&gt;. Asciiquarium screensaver moves from kdereview to kdeartwork. Kugar and koshell are removed from &lt;a href="http://koffice.org/"&gt;KOffice&lt;/a&gt; 2. &lt;a href="http://commit-digest.org/issues/2008-09-14/"&gt;Read the rest of the Digest here&lt;/a&gt;.


           </description>
           <link>http://dot.kde.org/1221784611/</link>
           <guid>http://dot.kde.org/1221784611/</guid>
           <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 17:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
           </item>
        </channel>
    </rss>
